Yale Peabody Museum Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
- Stanley N. Botwinik Slide Collection, 1968-1982; Series I
  - Grand Cayman., 000059
    - Peacock flounder. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Dec 1978., 000347
    - Plume worms. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Dec 1978., 000348
    - Queen angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Dec 1978., 000349
    - Plume worms. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Dec 1978., 000350
    - Gray angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Dec 1978., 000351
    - Squid (nite). British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Dec 1978., 000352
    - Sea slug. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000364
    - Spiny lobster. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000365
    - Octopus. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000366
    - Octopus. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000367
    - Octopus. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000368
    - Purple club-tipped anenomes. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000369
    - Flamingo tongues. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000370
    - Gray angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000371
    - Blue tang. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000372
    - Sea slug. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000373
    - Hermit crab. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000374
    - Spotted moray eel. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000375
    - Gray angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000376
    - Gray angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Jun 1979., 000377
    - Sea urchin. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000378
    - Plume worm. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000379
    - Princess parrotfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000380
    - Flamingo tongue. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000381
    - Hermit crab. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000382
    - Crinoid. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000383
    - Vase sponge. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000384
    - Vase sponge. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000385
    - Fire coral. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000386
    - Tube sponges. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000387
    - Gorgonian. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000388
    - Anemone. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000389
    - Damselfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000390
    - Damselfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000391
    - Damselfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000392
    - Brain coral (close-up). British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000393
    - Gray angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000394
    - Queen angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000395
    - Blue tang. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000396
    - Anemone. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000397
    - Plume worm. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000398
    - Plume worm. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000399
    - Balloon fish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1979., 000400
    - Tube sponges. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000401
    - Bluestriped grunt. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000402
    - Big eye. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000403
    - French angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000404
    - Gray angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000405
    - Flamingo tongue. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000406
    - Gray angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000407
    - French angelfish and trumpetfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000408
    - Nassau Grouper. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000409
    - Squirrel fish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000410
    - Goby. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000411
    - Vase sponges. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000412
    - Fire coral. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000413
    - Scrawled filefish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000414
    - Vase sponge. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000415
    - Finger sponge. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000416
    - Diver. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000417
    - Diver. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1979., 000418
    - Balboa. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000419
    - Balboa. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000420
    - Balboa. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000421
    - Balboa. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000422
    - Balboa. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000423
    - Balboa. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000424
    - Balboa. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000425
    - Sea slug. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000426
    - Orange filefish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000427
    - Orange filefish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000428
    - Banded butterflyfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000429
    - Damselfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000430
    - Flamingo tongue. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000431
    - Feather dusters. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000432
    - Orange filefish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000433
    - Hogfish (nite). British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000434
    - Doctor fishes (night). British West Indies, Grand Cayman. May 1980., 000435
    - Gray angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1980., 000465
    - Gray angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1980., 000466
    - Gray angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1980., 000467
    - Gray angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1980., 000468
    - Barracuda. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1980., 000469
    - Blue tang. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1980., 000470
    - Sting ray. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1980., 000471
    - Queen triggerfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1980., 000472
    - Spiny lobster. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1980., 000473
    - Flamingo tongue. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1980., 000474
    - Gray angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1980., 000475
    - French angelfish. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1980., 000476
    - Pillar coral. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Nov 1980., 000477
    - Crinoid. British West Indies, Grand Cayman. Aug 1982., 000493
  - Hudson Bay., 000063
    - Walrus. Canada, Hudson Bay, Walrus Island. Aug 1974., 000218
    - Walrus. Canada, Hudson Bay, Walrus Island. Aug 1974., 000219
    - Walrus. Canada, Hudson Bay, Walrus Island. Aug 1974., 000220
    - Walrus. Canada, Hudson Bay, Walrus Island. Aug 1974., 000221
    - Walrus. Canada, Hudson Bay, Walrus Island. Aug 1974., 000222
    - Walrus. Canada, Hudson Bay, Walrus Island. Aug 1974., 000223
  - Mexico., 000061
    - Queen aneglfish. Mexico, Cozumel. Nov 1975., 000225
    - Queen aneglfish. Mexico, Cozumel. Nov 1975., 000226
    - Rock beauties. Mexico, Cozumel. Nov 1975., 000227
    - Anemone. Mexico, Cozumel. Nov 1975., 000228
    - Blue tang. Mexico, Cozumel. Nov 1975., 000229
    - Vase sponge. Mexico, Cozumel. Nov 1975., 000230
    - Vase sponge. Mexico, Cozumel. Nov 1975., 000231
    - Sponges. Mexico, Cozumel. Nov 1975., 000232
  - Miscellaneous., 000070
    - Sepik men. Tahiti, Papeete. Sep 1969., 000107
    - Countryside. Australia, Melbourne, Mackenzie Sanctuary. Sep 1969., 000111
    - Austral caracara. Falkland Islands, New Island. Mar 1974., 000216
    - Black-browed albatross feeding chick. Falkland Islands, West Point Island. Mar 1974., 000217
    - Grouper (tiger). Bahamas, Andros Island. Apr 1976., 000236
    - Queen angelfish. Bahamas, Grand Bahama. Apr 1977., 000259
    - Queen angelfish. Bahamas, Grand Bahama. Apr 1977., 000260
    - Vermont farm. United States, Vermont., 000494
    - Zebra poster (faux colors). Africa., 000495
    - Skiers. Austria, St. Anton., 000496
    - Llama. Peru, Cuzco. Jan 1972., 000502
  - New Guinea., 000067
    - Sepik. New Guinea, Minj. Sep 1969., 000104
    - Sepik young man. New Guinea, Minj. Sep 1969., 000105
    - Sepik Sing Sing. New Guinea, Minj. Sep 1969., 000106
    - Native village. Papua, Wanigela. Sep 1969., 000109
    - Beach and sea. New Guinea, Minj. Sep 1969., 000110
  - Palau., 000069
    - Green moray eel. Micronesia, Palau. May 1981., 000478
    - Clown fish. Micronesia, Palau. May 1981., 000479
    - Soft coral. Micronesia, Palau. May 1981., 000480
    - Soft coral (close-up). Micronesia, Palau. May 1981., 000481
    - Sea turtle. Micronesia, Palau. May 1981., 000482
    - Sea turtle. Micronesia, Palau. May 1981., 000483
    - Crinoid. Micronesia, Palau. May 1981., 000484
    - Crinoid (close-up). Micronesia, Palau. May 1981., 000485
    - Crinoid (close-up). Micronesia, Palau. May 1981., 000486
  - Red Sea., 000065
    - Clown fish. The Red Sea. May 1979., 000353
    - Clown fish. The Red Sea. May 1979., 000354
    - Lion fish. The Red Sea. May 1979., 000355
    - Basket star. The Red Sea. May 1979., 000356
    - Grouper. The Red Sea. May 1979., 000357
    - Wrasse. The Red Sea. May 1979., 000358
    - Basket star. The Red Sea. May 1979., 000359
    - Clownfish. The Red Sea. May 1979., 000360
    - Queen angelfish. The Red Sea. May 1979., 000361
    - Grouper. The Red Sea. May 1979., 000362
    - Gold fishes. The Red Sea. May 1979., 000363
- [Untitled], Series II
  Miscellaneous Museum Archives
  - Peabody blueprints. 19 original blueprint sheets from 1923 of the Peabody Museum by architects Day and Klauder, Philadelphia, PA., 21 Mar 1923 - 20 Jul 1923; 001027
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-86, Porch vaulting diagram and details of tas de charge., 20 Jul 1923; 001046
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-2, Basement plan., 21 Mar 1923 - 11 Jun 1923; 001029
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-3, First floor plan., 21 Mar 1923 - 11 Jun 1923; 001030
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-4, Second floor plan., 21 Mar 1923 - 11 Jun 1923; 001031
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-5, Third floor plan., 21 Mar 1923 - 11 Jun 1923; 001032
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-14, Various details and sections, 21 Mar 1923 - 11 Jun 1923; 001041
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-15, Main stair plan, 21 Mar 1923 - 11 Jun 1923; 001042
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-9, West elevation., 21 Mar 1923 - 20 Jul 1923; 001036
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-7, East elevation., 21 Mar 1923 - 28 Jun 1923; 001034
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-11, Sections A-A and B-B., 21 Mar 1923 - 28 Jun 1923; 001038
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-12, Sections C-C and others., 21 Mar 1923 - 28 Jun 1923; 001039
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-13, Main entrance elevation, 21 Mar 1923 - 30 Jul 1923; 001040
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-1, Plot plan., 21 Mar 1923; 001028
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-6, Roof and tower floor plan., 21 Mar 1923; 001033
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-8, South elevation., 21 Mar 1923; 001035
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-10, North elevation., 21 Mar 1923; 001037
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-16, Stair details, 21 Mar 1923; 001043
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-17, Section details, 21 Mar 1923; 001044
    - Peabody blueprint. Sheet 900-25, Foundation and footing plan., 8 Jun 1923; 001045
  - Miscellaneous photographs, slides, sketches and other material., 000526
    - Age of Reptiles Mural in process. Black and white photograph of Rudolph Zallinger working on Age or Reptiles mural., 000530
    - Art supplies. Pigments, sage brushes, casein, and pallette of Zallinger, used for the Age of Mammals mural., 000881
    - Book. "An Account of the Meteor" Memoirs of the Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1810, Authors: Benjamin Silliman and James L. Kingsley., 000897
    - Brontosaur with Lull and Gibb. Black and white photograph of Lull and Gibb with mounted Brotosaurus in Peabody Museum Great Hall., 000541
    - Carboniferous Forest diorama. Black and white photograph of the Peabody Museum Carboniferous Forest diorama., 000540
    - Carboniferous forest postcard. Black and white postcard of Peabody Museum Carboniferous Forest diorama., 000539
    - Custer Wagon Train. Black and white photograph of Custer wagon train., 000545
    - Deed of Gift. Deed of Gift, Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History, 1866., 000878
    - Exhibition Hall Guide. General Guide to the Exhibition Halls of the Peabody Museum., 000546
    - Foucault Pendulum. Black and white image of Foucault Pendulum in Peabody Museum lobby., 000547
    - Fresco. Detail from Carbonaceous Forest diorama, Invertebrate Hall, Peabody Museum. Artist: Robert Bruct Horsfall (1869 - 1948), 1926; 000891
    - Gibb Torosaurus Pteranodon. Black and white photograph of Hugh Gibb with skull of Torosaurus and Pteranodon in background., 000536
    - Great Hall 1924. Black and white image of Peabody Museum Great Hall, 1924., 000548
    - Great Hall 1925. Black and white photograph of Peabody Museum Great Hall, 1925., 000535
    - Great Hall Dedication. Black and white photograph of dedication of Peabody Museum Great Hall., 000542
    - Gregory Gargantua. Black and white photograph of Gregory holding skull of Gargantua., 000532
    - Harry Townshend. Scrap book of Harry Townshend's giant squid that contains: newspaper and magazine articles, photos of squid reinstallation, and "A Summary of the Giant Squid and Research by Deb Townshend"., 000906
    - Horse Case Postcard. Black and white postcard of Evolution of Horses exhibit case in Peabody Museum., 000549
    - Huxley Letter 1876, reverse. Letter from Thomas Huxley, 1876, reverse., 000551
    - Huxley letter 1876. Front of letter from Thomas Huxley, 1876., 000550
    - Invertebrate Hall case. Black and white image of case in Peabody Museum Invertebrate Hall., 000553
    - Invertebrate Hall. Black and white image of Peabody Museum Invertebrate Hall., 000552
    - JD Dana Vesuvius. Page 266 of James Dwight Dana's "Manual of Geology" showing Dana's drawing of Vesuvius., 000554
    - John Bell Hatcher. Black and white photograph of John Bell Hatcher., 000529
    - Katherine Bush. Black and white photograph of Katherine Bush, Charlotte Bush, M. J. Rathbun, and Eloise Edwards., 000555
    - Letter. Letter from Charles Darwin to O.C. Marsh., 31 Aug 1880; 000895
    - Magazine. LIFE magazine featuring study for Age of Mammals., 19 Oct 1953; 000883
    - Magazine. Facsimile reprint of The Audubon Magazine, Vol. 1, No. 1, February 1887., 1987; 000745
    - Magazine. LIFE magazine featuring study for Age of Reptiles., 7 Sep 1953; 000882
    - Mastadon. Black and white photograph of mounted Mastadon., 000556
    - Medal. A.E. Verrill medal., 000741
    - Mineral Hall. Black and white photograph of original mineral hall case with specimens., 000903
    - Mineral Hall. Black and white photograph of original mineral hall., 000904
    - Mineral Hall. Black and white photograph of mineral hall from the original Peabody Museum building, 000905
    - Monograph. George R. Wieland's copy of O.C. Marsh's "Fossil Horses in America", 1874; 000896
    - Morrill Shore Diorama. Black and white photograph of Morrill working on shore diorama., 000537
    - Mounting Bronotsaurus. Black and white photograph of Bronotsaurus being mounted in Peabody Museum Great Hall., 000544
    - Oil tank mural. 35mm color negatives or the Peabody Museum mural on oil tank at New Haven harbor., 000557
    - Osteological collection. Black and white photograph of osteological collection in Peabody Museum., 000534
    - Painting. "Junction of the Platte Rivers", 1866, by Thomas Worthington Whittredge, American (1820-1910), 000742
    - Painting. "Santa Fe", July 20, 1866, by Thomas Worthington Whittredge, American (1820-1910), 000743
    - Painting. Spanish Peaks from Raton Pass", 1866, by Thomas Worthington Whittredge, American (1820-1910), 000744
    - Painting. Painting of O.C. Marsh by Rudolph Zallinger., 000740
    - Painting. Oil on canvas painting of George Peabody (1895 - 1869). Unknown date and artist. Gift of the Estate of Othniel Charles Marsh, 1899., 000898
    - Parsons Eagle. Black and white photograph of Dave Parsons working on mounting a eagle on a branch., 000528
    - Parsons Neanderthal. Color photograph of Dave Parsons with Neanderthal model., 000531
    - Peabody Museum lobby 1925. Black and white image of Peabody Museum lobby, 1925., 000558
    - Peabody Museum under construction. Black and white photograph of Yale Peabody Museum under construction., 000533
    - Perry Wilson Shore Diorama. Black and white photograph of Perry Wilson working on shore diorama., 000527
    - Photograph. Black and white photograph of Wieland in Great Hall., 08 Nov 1931; 000890
    - Photograph. Photograph of G. Evelyn Hutchinson taken by David Furth at Wicken Fen, United Kingdom., 23 Mar 1991; 001026
    - Photograph. Portrait of A.E. Verrill, 000876
    - Photograph. Black and white photograph of the Peabody Museum building under construction., 000887
    - Photograph. Black and white photograph of Lull and Gibb with mounted Brontosaurus skeleton., 000888
    - Photograph. Black and white photograph of Great Hall dedication ceremony., 000889
    - Photograph. Timber Line Diorama, 000892
    - Photograph. Model of Timber Line Diorama, Peabody Museum., 000893
    - Photograph. Life-sized model of Architeuthis dux, 1883, papier-mache, length 12.2m (40ft). Designed by A.E. Verrill. Artist, James H Emerton., 000894
    - Postcard. Postcard of the Yale tennis court at Whitney and Sachem., 000884
    - Primate skeletons. Black and white photograph of evolution of primate skeletons display., 000538
    - Pteranodon 1925. Black and white photograph of Pteranodon mounted in Great Hall, 1925., 000559
    - Publication. American Journal of Science, Vol. 1, Issue 1, belonging to Benjamin Silliman., 000877
    - Remington. Black and white photograph of Charles Remington inspecting insect damage to a book., 000560
    - Sketch. Early sketch, Age of Reptiles, Rudolph F. Zallinger., 000879
    - Sketch. Early sketch, Age of Mammals, Rudolph F. Zallinger., 000880
    - Thomson with Coelacanth. Series of black and white photographs of Thomson examining coelacanth., 000543
    - Vincennes. Drawing on page 256 of ship Vincennes on San Francisco bar., 000561